<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Current projects | Tichakorn (Nok) Wongpiromsarn</title>
    <link>https://tichakorn832.github.io/tag/current-projects/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tichakorn832.github.io/tag/current-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Current projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://tichakorn832.github.io/img/nok.png</url>
      <title>Current projects</title>
      <link>https://tichakorn832.github.io/tag/current-projects/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formal Specifications of Autonomous Systems</title>
      <link>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/formal-specifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/formal-specifications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A specification for a system describes its admissible behaviors and formalizes its properties. Many existing design and verification efforts, particularly those based on formal methods, assume the availability of such specifications. However, this assumption has been proved to be a major problem of its own, as witnessed in many CPS applications that integrate autonomy. The lack of precise specifications is a significant impediment towards formal methods realizing their full potential in this domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to provide theory, methods, and tools to derive, analyze, and refine specifications for systems subject to regulatory requirements. Our approach integrates formal methods, learning-based approaches, and game-theoretic frameworks, and utilize complementary sources of information, namely the textual information from the regulatory requirements and the demonstrations, taking into account their imperfection such as ambiguity, incompleteness, labeling errors, and uncertainties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning with Conflicting Specifications</title>
      <link>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/planning-conflicting-specifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/planning-conflicting-specifications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Autonomous systems may be subject to several requirements. Consider, as an example, autonomous vehicles that need to follow the road rules. Often, these rules cannot be simultaneously satisfied. For instance, when encoutering a vehicle that is (improperly) parked next to the solid line, an autonomous vehicle may need to violate the lane keeping rule (which prohibits the vehicle from crossing solid lane boundary) or the obstacle clearance rule (which requires the vehicle to keep some safety gap when passing a parked vehicle). Another example is the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trolley_problem&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;trolley problem&lt;/a&gt; where autonomous systems need to choose which safety requirements to violate. More complications arise when taking into account uncertainties, e.g., in perception, prediction, control, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to develop planning and decision-making algorithms for systems that are subject to multiple, potentially conflicting objectives. These objectives may be represented by a combination of cost functions (e.g., control efforts) and temporal logic formulas (e.g., rules of the road), with associated violation metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
