<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Past projects | Tichakorn (Nok) Wongpiromsarn</title>
    <link>https://tichakorn832.github.io/tag/past-projects/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tichakorn832.github.io/tag/past-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Past projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://tichakorn832.github.io/img/nok.png</url>
      <title>Past projects</title>
      <link>https://tichakorn832.github.io/tag/past-projects/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning with Conflicting Specifications</title>
      <link>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/planning-conflicting-specifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/planning-conflicting-specifications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Autonomous systems may be subject to several requirements. Consider, as an example, autonomous vehicles that need to follow the road rules. Often, these rules cannot be simultaneously satisfied. For instance, when encoutering a vehicle that is (improperly) parked next to the solid line, an autonomous vehicle may need to violate the lane keeping rule (which prohibits the vehicle from crossing solid lane boundary) or the obstacle clearance rule (which requires the vehicle to keep some safety gap when passing a parked vehicle). Another example is the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trolley_problem&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;trolley problem&lt;/a&gt; where autonomous systems need to choose which safety requirements to violate. More complications arise when taking into account uncertainties, e.g., in perception, prediction, control, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to develop planning and decision-making algorithms for systems that are subject to multiple, potentially conflicting objectives. These objectives may be represented by a combination of cost functions (e.g., control efforts) and temporal logic formulas (e.g., rules of the road), with associated violation metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formal Specifications of Autonomous Systems</title>
      <link>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/formal-specifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/formal-specifications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A specification for a system describes its admissible behaviors and formalizes its properties. Many existing design and verification efforts, particularly those based on formal methods, assume the availability of such specifications. However, this assumption has been proved to be a major problem of its own, as witnessed in many CPS applications that integrate autonomy. The lack of precise specifications is a significant impediment towards formal methods realizing their full potential in this domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to provide theory, methods, and tools to derive, analyze, and refine specifications for systems subject to regulatory requirements. Our approach integrates formal methods, learning-based approaches, and game-theoretic frameworks, and utilize complementary sources of information, namely the textual information from the regulatory requirements and the demonstrations, taking into account their imperfection such as ambiguity, incompleteness, labeling errors, and uncertainties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autonomy in Mobility-on-Demand Systems</title>
      <link>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/mobility-on-demand/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/mobility-on-demand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the use of private vehicles starts approaching its limits to effectively meet the demand for personal mobility in densely populated cities, mobility-on-demand (MoD) systems emerge as a more economical and sustainable alternative. These systems rely on the deployment of a fleet of vehicles at different stations that are distributed throughout the city. The customers simply have to walk to a station near their origin, pick up a vehicle, drive it to the station near to their destination and drop it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project is to assess and demonstrate the role of autonomy in mobility-on-demand systems through modeling, algorithm development and experimental demonstration. We have instrumented a golf cart and demonstrated basic autonomous driving capabilities, including reliable navigation in a GPS-denied environment and safe interaction with automotive and pedestrian traffic. Unlike most existing autonomous vehicles, our golf cart uses minimal sensing and off-the-shelf components to attain the same level of operational ability while keeping the system economically viable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mdsoU4Udi-M&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time Control and Learning for Sustainable Transportation</title>
      <link>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/sustainable-transportation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/sustainable-transportation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Traffic congestion causes significant efficiency losses, wasteful energy consumption and excessive air pollution. This problem arises in many urban areas because of the continual growth in motorization and the difficulties in increasing road capacity due to space limitations and budget constraints. As a result, traffic management that aims at maximizing the efficiency and effectiveness of road networks without increasing road capacity becomes increasingly crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project focuses on mechanism design for dynamic pricing and real-time control of traffic signals based on control, communication, optimization and game theory in order to manage traffic flows in an optimal manner and minimize traffic congestion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Sk-d5-cfkDk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consensus Approaches to the Assignment Problem</title>
      <link>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/consensus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/consensus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The assignment problem, also regarded as the bipartite Maximum Weighted Matching problem, is a fundamental problem in combinatorial optimization and provides several applications, especially in the areas of multi-agent coordination, distributed computing and distributed manufacturing. In particular, it has been shown that optimal task and resource allocation can be reduced to an instance of the assignment problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work aims at designing a consensus protocol to solve the assignment problem in a completely distributed manner without any central management or global knowledge. The main application of this work is sensor dispatch, an emerging problem in wireless sensor networks where a subset of mobile sensors need to decide how to move in order to optimize certain global objectives while maintaining the coverage ability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formal Methods for Design and Verification of Embedded Control Systems</title>
      <link>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/formal-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/formal-methods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The design of reliable embedded control systems inherits the difficulties involved in designing both control systems and distributed (concurrent) computing systems. Design bugs in these systems may arise from the unforeseen interactions among the computing, communication and control subsystems. Motivated by the difficulties of finding this type of design bugs, this project focuses on developing mathematical frameworks, based on formal methods, to facilitate the design and analysis of such embedded systems. This work incorporates methodology from computer science and control, including model checking, theorem proving, synthesis of digital designs, reachability analysis, Lyapunov-type methods and receding horizon control. Various applications have been considered, including autonomy, vehicle management and multi-target tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3HMOa-UsSPc&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DARPA Urban Challenge 2007</title>
      <link>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/darpa-urban-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/darpa-urban-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project involves building an autonomous ground vehicle capable of maneuvering a 60 mile course in a mock urban environment in less than 6 hours. As the coordinator of the Systems team, my contribution to this project is the development of a new software architecture for distributed goal and contingency management which is the main part of the mission management subsystem. I have also implemented the decision making logic of the planning module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;





  
  











&lt;figure class=&#34;img-sm&#34; id=&#34;figure-alice-in-the-2007-darpa-urban-challenge&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/darpa-urban-challenge/team-duc_huaef21ced083e51a4dc13eda5d05f018f_360779_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Alice in the 2007 DARPA Urban Challenge&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/darpa-urban-challenge/team-duc_huaef21ced083e51a4dc13eda5d05f018f_360779_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;1600&#34; height=&#34;1071&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Alice in the 2007 DARPA Urban Challenge
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  
  











&lt;figure class=&#34;img-sm&#34; id=&#34;figure-site-visit&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/darpa-urban-challenge/team-site_huc06d5c3b9581a85bad4aab7bd4d4fa53_100758_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Site visit&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/darpa-urban-challenge/team-site_huc06d5c3b9581a85bad4aab7bd4d4fa53_100758_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;902&#34; height=&#34;600&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Site visit
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1eZdc1hsBkU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstraction-Based Multi-Vehicle Command and Control</title>
      <link>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/planning-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tichakorn832.github.io/project/planning-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This work introduces an encapsulation approach to path planning for multi-vehicle control that permits other decision processes to work with simple, spatially-abstracted domain models, and partially or wholly ignore obstacles, observation uncertainty and vehicle dynamics. Application to multi-vehicle command and control has been considered.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
